In order to represent the graph, we have two types.
The adjacency metrics and that adjacency list, we have learned about the adjacency metrics and its
sort of presentation.
Now let's make a program in see that implement the adjacency metrics.
And later on in the next video, we are going to learn about the adjacency metrics, implementation
and Java.
And next step, we are going to see the other presentation of a graph, which is that Jason S. Lest.
Let's define vehicle for initialize the metrics to zero.
We initialize the metrics here by creating a new method for returning type void, and it took into the
perimeter int array of two dimensional array.
It's very important and in the number of columns is V, which is for in this example, it can make it
whatever you want.
I will create two nested loops, so when dealing with two dimensional array, I am going to deal with
the array of two loops, two nested loops.
From equal to zero and I less than V I plus plus, so go through all the rows and from Jay equal to
zero J, let's them V and G Plus Plus, so go through all the columns I array at index I.J equal to
zero and shallows all the metrics to zero.
So so there is no connection between any of the purchases until this.
So this method just enclosing the metrics to zero.
Now let's add the edges.
We create a new method called add edge.
It's returning type is void and it took into the parameters do.
Parameters that end in dimension, a two dimensional array, and if of size zero is not defined, we
defined it later and the columns is V, which is for it took int i and it j.
We start internalizing I j equal to one J I equal to one.
This is why we add the edges.
OK.
We are creating a connection between them, so if we specify equal to two and a J equal to three, so
two, three, equal to one and three to equal to one, this is undirected.
Graph goes forward that we have an adjacency metrics now to print the metrics.
We print the adjacency metrics by specifying and creating and a method called print adjacency matrix
and specify that in in that parameters, the entire array of two dimensional array.
The array a graph.
OK.
And we create I and J since we are going to print the two dimensional array we need to make at two nested
loops and we print array at Index II and Index J.
OK, now let's test our program.
We create an adjacent matrix called adjacent Matrix V with the same size, so for four initialized the
adjacent matrix.
So all the 16 elements are 16 cells would be initialized to zero, then add the edge met.
We post the matrix here and zero and one.
So the connection between zero zero zero and column one would be one, and the connection between row
one and column zero would be one.
According to the add edge algorithm here.
So we passed here zero and one.
We replace array at index zero one.
There is a connection and array between one and zero.
There is a connection.
OK.
So when we draw the table here, this is I.
Rose, this is the column, so.
When we throw their columns here.
So zero.
One, zero, one and two and until four.
So between zero and zero, there is no connection till now, zero and one there is connection and between
one and zero connection.
So we create two connections do we put two ones ED when we call the method at ATCH?
OK?
It's very simple.
Now add edge between zero and two and two and zero put one between one and two and two one two zero
zero two two three three two.
And now let's bring that Jason Matrix.
It would end returning zero for the me.
I want from you to put your.
And write this code into your compiler, see and and let me show it, let me see in the comments your
output.
So and tell me what it's happening inside this program, I lectured for you enough for making and understanding
it without compilers, but I prefer you to write the code in the compiler, and I want from you to put
it in the comments.
Any solution of this exercise?
And also, if you have any doubt, any recommendation and these suggestions for our courses and to improve
our later videos, please comment below.
In order to make our courses and better and I like to to see the comments.